[Plankton humming]
[浮游生物的嗡嗡声]
- Oh, Planky-bear.
- 哦，板条熊。
Plankton.
浮游生物。
- [continues humming]
- [继续哼唱]
- Plankton!
- 浮游生物！
- What?
- 什么？
What is it, Karen?
这是什么，凯伦？
Can't you see
I'm working here?
你看不到吗
我在这里工作？
- Yes, but I wanted to show you
- 是的，但我想给你看
my new screen saver.
我的新屏幕保护程序。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
- Great.
- 伟大的。
- You didn't even look.
- 你连看都没看。
- [sighs]
No, I didn't.
- [叹气]
不，我没有。
Can't you see
I'm working on
你看不到吗
我正在努力
my new molecular analyzer?
我的新分子分析仪？
Now all I need is the
smallest molecule of a patty,
现在我需要的是
肉饼的最小分子，
and the formula
will be mine!
和公式
将是我的！
- Just tell me if I should
- 告诉我是否应该
permanently upload
this screen saver!
永久上传
这个屏幕保护程序！
- I said not...
- 我说不是...
[lever clicks, tube hisses]
Now-ow-ow!
[杠杆咔嗒声，管子嘶嘶声]
现在-噢-噢！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[Plankton whooshes]
Ow!
[浮游生物呼啸]
噢！
[loud smash]
[大声粉碎]
[gasping]
[喘气]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
[snaps, yelping]
[啪啪，尖叫]
[electricity zaps,
Plankton screams]
[电击，
浮游生物尖叫]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Analyzing.
- 分析。
30% mean guy,
30% 刻薄的人，
20% spiteful monster,
20%恶毒的怪物，
50% evil butthead.
50%邪恶的屁股。
Sample is...
样本是...
100% big jerk.
100%大混蛋。
- [grunting, yelps]
- [咕哝，尖叫]
- I have also analyzed
——我也分析过
your screen saver,
Karen.
你的屏幕保护程序，
凯伦。
It is most beautiful.
它是最美丽的。
- No one asked you.
- 没有人问你。
[loud smash]
[大声粉碎]
Are you happy now, Karen?
凯伦，你现在幸福吗？
- No, I'm not.
- 不，我不是。
I was just trying to
make myself pretty for you,
我只是想
为了你，把自己打扮得漂漂亮亮的
but do you even care?
但你关心吗？
All you ever do
is make stupid schemes
你所做的一切
正在制定愚蠢的计划
about stupid sandwiches!
关于愚蠢的三明治！
- Stupid?
- 愚蠢的？
Your new screen saver
is stupid,
您的新屏幕保护程序
是愚蠢的，
and it makes your processor
look fat!
它使你的处理器
看起来很胖！
[explosions]
[爆炸]
- What?
- 什么？
- Oop.
- 哎呀。
Okay, let's all calm down
好吧，让我们都冷静下来
before you say something
you'll regret.
在你说些什么之前
你会后悔的。
- You know what?
- 你知道吗？
No one talks to me
like that.
没有人跟我说话
像那样。
Get out!
出去！
- I will not get out.
- 我不会出去。
This is my restaurant,
这是我的餐厅，
and no one can make me...
而没有人能让我...
leave!
离开！
[thuds]
Ow!
[重击声]
噢！
Karen, baby.
凯伦，宝贝。
Come on, sugar lips,
来吧，糖唇，
you know I'm sorry
for everything I said.
你知道我很抱歉
对于我所说的一切。
[portcullis thuds,
Plankton yelps]
[闸门重击，
浮游生物尖叫]
- I accept your apology.
- 我接受你的道歉。
- I wasn't talking to you,
idiot!
-我不是在跟你说话
白痴！
[squishes, Plankton screams]
[压扁，浮游生物尖叫]
Pain!
疼痛！
Okay, Karen, fun is fun,
好吧，凯伦，有趣就是有趣，
but it's time to let me back in.
但现在是让我回去的时候了。
Come on, I really
need to use the potty!
来吧，我真的
需要使用便盆！
[metal doors thud, lasers hum]
[金属门砰的一声，激光发出嗡嗡声]
Fine, I don't need you
or the Chum Bucket!
好吧，我不需要你
或者密友桶！
I got plenty of friends
around here
我有很多朋友
在这附近
who would love to take me in.
谁愿意带我进去。
So is it cool if I crash here?
- No.
那么如果我在这里崩溃是不是很酷？
- 不。
- Then can I just
use your bath room?
- 那我可以吗
使用你的浴室吗？
[thuds, yelps]
[重击声，尖叫声]
- Plankton, I know
where this is going.
- 浮游生物，我知道
这是怎么回事。
I'd love it
if you'd stay with me!
我会喜欢的
如果你愿意留在我身边！
- Are you crazy?
- 你疯了？
You're the most annoying sponge
in the sea.
你是最烦人的海绵
在海里。
I wouldn't stay with you
我不会和你呆在一起
if you were the last person
in Bikini Bottom.
如果你是最后一个人
在比基尼底部。
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
- Suit yourself.
- 适合你自己。
[slurping resumes]
[吞咽简历]
- Okay, fine!
- 好吧，好吧！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[toilet flushes]
[厕所冲水]
Whew!
哇！
Much better.
好多了。
Thanks for letting me
use your bathroom.
谢谢你让我
使用你的浴室。
- [laughs]
Silly, that's not my bathroom.
- [笑]
傻了，那不是我的浴室。
- Well, in that case,
- 那么，在这种情况下，
you're gonna need
some new shoes.
你会需要
一些新鞋。
- Oh, boy!
- 哦，孩子！
Does this mean
you're gonna stay with me?
这是否意味着
你会留下来陪我吗？
- Yes!
- 是的！
- Yeah!
[celebratory fanfare]
[庆祝的乐曲]
We're gonna be
the best roommates ever!
我们将会是
有史以来最好的室友！
Oh!
Wanna do each other's hair?
哦！
想给对方做头发吗？
[laughs]
- Oh, forget this!
[笑]
- 哦，忘了这个吧！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Oh, my love,
what a fool I've been.
- 哦，我的爱人，
我真是个傻瓜。
You've always been
the only one for me.
你一直都是
唯一适合我的。
[both smooching]
[两人接吻]
- [sniffling]
- [抽鼻子]
- Aw, Plankton.
- 噢，浮游生物。
I am so sorry that
我很抱歉
Karen threw you out.
凯伦把你赶了出去。
- Threw me out?
- 把我赶出去？
I threw her in!
我把她扔进去了！
- Hey, this is
your safe place.
- 嘿，这是
你安全的地方。
It's okay to talk about
your feelings.
没关系谈论
你的感受。
Oh, somebody's tense!
哦，有人紧张！
- Hey!
What?
- 嘿！
什么？
Get off!
下车！
Get--Oh!
得到——哦！
[moaning, laughs]
[呻吟，大笑]
Oh,
that's the spot.
哦，
就是那个地方。
- Now, tell SpongeBob why
you and Karen got into a fight.
- 现在，告诉海绵宝宝为什么
你和凯伦打架了。
- I don't know,
I was just doing
- 我不知道，
我刚刚在做
the same things I always do.
我总是做同样的事情。
- Well, if Karen
threw you out
- 好吧，如果凯伦
把你赶出去
for doing the same things
you always do,
为了做同样的事情
你总是这样做，
maybe you should learn
to not do
也许你应该学习
不做
the same things
you always do!
同样的事情
你总是这样！
- But I'm the best.
- 但我是最好的。
- Well, sometimes
you can get a little...
- 嗯，有时
你可以得到一点...
aggressive.
挑衅的。
- Me, aggressive?
- 我，有攻击性？
How dare you?
你怎么敢？
[smacking and grunting]
[咂嘴和咕哝]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Maybe you're right.
也许你是对的。
I can be a big jerk
sometimes.
我可能是个大混蛋
有时。
I command you to help me
be a nicer person!
我命令你帮助我
做一个更好的人！
I mean, will you please,
我的意思是，请你，
please help me
be a nicer person
请帮助我
做一个更好的人
so Karen
will take me back?
苏凯伦
会带我回去吗？
- Plankton, in a word: yes!
- 浮游生物，一句话：是的！
- What is that dimwit
doing here?
- 那个傻瓜是什么
在这里做什么？
- Ahh!
Oh, behind me!
- 啊！
噢，在我身后！
Oh, get away!
噢，走开！
- Will you stop that?
- 你能阻止吗？
There's no one behind you!
你身后没有人！
You're the dimwit.
你就是那个笨蛋。
- Oh.
- 哦。
Thanks!
谢谢！
- All right, Plankton,
- 好吧，浮游生物，
the first step
to becoming a nicer person
第一步
成为一个更好的人
is being thoughtful.
正在深思熟虑。
Try holding a door
for someone.
尝试扶着门
对于某人。
It's simple,
and it makes people happy.
很简单，
它使人们快乐。
Like this.
像这样。
After you.
您先请。
- [laughs]
I'm happy, SpongeBob!
- [笑]
我很高兴，海绵宝宝！
[smooches]
[亲吻]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Can someone
get me out of here?
- 有人可以吗
带我离开这里？
Whew!
哇！
- All right, Plankton.
Now you try!
- 好吧，浮游生物。
现在你试试吧！
- Fine, but if he kisses me,
I'm gonna lose it.
- 好吧，但如果他吻我，
我会失去它。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Ugh.
After you.
- 呃。
您先请。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[continues grunting]
[继续咕哝]
Whoa!
哇！
- Try this one.
- 试试这个。
- After you.
- 您先请。
- But I can't fit through there.
- 但我无法通过那里。
- How dare you
reject my act of kindness!
- 你怎么敢
拒绝我的善举！
Yah!
- Ahh!
啊！
- 啊！
[Patrick thuds,
Plankton smacks and grunts]
[帕特里克重击，
浮游生物拍打着并发出咕噜声]
- Plankton, no!
- 浮游生物，不！
- Can someone
get me out of here?
- 有人可以吗
带我离开这里？
- [Plankton smacks and grunts]
- [sighs]
- [浮游生物拍打和咕噜声]
- [叹气]
Okay, Plankton,
好吧，浮游生物，
since you don't seem to be able
to do something nice,
因为你似乎无法
做一些美好的事情，
in this lesson
you're going to learn
在本课中
你将会学到
to say something nice.
说一些好话。
- Easy!
- 简单的！
- Great.
- 伟大的。
So turn to Patrick
and say something nice.
所以转向帕特里克
并说一些好听的话。
- Say something nice.
- 说一些好听的话。
- Uh...
- 呃...
Patrick,
you are not a total moron.
帕特里克，
你不是个十足的白痴。
Just half of one.
只有一半。
- No, try again.
- 不，再试一次。
- Fine.
- 美好的。
Your color pink
is not so repugnant.
你的颜色粉红色
并不是那么令人反感。
- Thanks!
- 谢谢！
I like...um...
我喜欢……嗯……
your antennas.
你的天线。
- What?
What's wrong with my antennas?
- 什么？
我的天线出了什么问题？
- Plankton, Patrick was
complimenting you.
- 浮游生物，帕特里克
恭维你。
- Yeah, right.
- 是的，对。
You two are mocking me!
你们两个在嘲笑我！
[smacking and grunting]
[咂嘴和咕哝]
- Hey, SpongeBob?
- 嘿，海绵宝宝？
Do you think
this is working?
你认为
这有效吗？
- No, I think we better
try something else.
- 不，我认为我们更好
尝试别的东西。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[gasps,panting]
[喘气，气喘吁吁]
It's no use, SpongeBob.
这是没有用的，海绵宝宝。
I'm just too brilliant
to be nice.
我只是太聪明了
表现得友善。
I'll never get Karen back now.
我现在永远不会让凯伦回来了。
- Oh, yes, you will!
- 哦，是的，你会的！
We obviously can't fix
your terrible insides,
我们显然无法修复
你可怕的内心，
but maybe, just maybe,
但也许，只是也许，
we can work on
your terrible outsides.
我们可以努力
你可怕的外表。
Makeover time!
改头换面时间到了！
[scissors snipping]
[剪刀剪断]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[laughs]
[笑]
[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- Brother.
- 兄弟。
*
- [laughing gleefully]
- [高兴地笑]
**
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
Forget it, SpongeBob.
忘了它吧，海绵宝宝。
Karen's the perfect woman:
凯伦是完美的女人：
so smart, so conniving.
如此聪明，如此纵容。
Ah, she's never
gonna take me back.
啊，她从来没有
会带我回去的
- Oh, yes, she is.
- 哦，是的，她是。
You just need to
do something big.
你只需要
做一些大事。
Be vulnerable, be sweet.
变得脆弱，变得甜蜜。
Show Karen your heart.
向凯伦展示你的心。
- That's a great idea!
- 这是个好主意！
I'll cook up a scheme
to make her jealous
我会制定一个计划
让她嫉妒
and crush her spirit!
并粉碎她的精神！
[laughs]
[笑]
- That wasn't even close
to what I said.
- 那还差得很远
我说的。
- Sure it was.
- 当然是。
And I know
just how to do it.
我知道
只是如何去做。
[mimics cat meow]
[模仿猫的叫声]
- Okay,
I feel uncomfortable.
- 好吧，
我感觉不舒服。
Plankton, are you sure
about this?
浮游生物，你确定吗？
关于这个？
- Of course I'm sure.
- 我当然确定。
Now, start doing
a robot voice.
现在，开始做
机器人的声音。
Remember, you're not
SpongeBob anymore;
请记住，你不是
不再是海绵宝宝了；
you're Shelby Naughtica.
你是谢尔比·诺蒂卡。
- [in robot voice]
Oh, I like that!
- [机器人声音]
哦，我喜欢那样！
Boop beep!
Beep boop boop!
噗噗！
嘟嘟嘟！
- Welcome
to the Chum Bucket!
- 欢迎
到密友桶！
Oh.
哦。
It's you.
是你。
What do you want?
你想要什么？
- Yes, hello.
- 是的，你好。
I would like your most
romantic table
我最想要的是你
浪漫的餐桌
for myself
and my beautiful date,
为我自己
和我美丽的约会对象，
Shelby Naughtica,
谢尔比·诺蒂卡,
the robot.
机器人。
- Beep boop!
[laughs robotically]
- 嘟嘟！
[机械地笑]
- Hmm.
- 唔。
Hmm.
唔。
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
Shelby Naughtica, huh?
谢尔比·诺蒂卡，是吧？
Oh, what
a beautiful name.
哦，什么
一个美丽的名字。
- Thank you!
- 谢谢你！
- [grunts]
- Ow!
- [咕哝]
- 噢！
[in robot voice]
I mean, thank you.
[机器人声音]
我的意思是，谢谢。
Whoa!
Beep boop beep bo boop!
哇！
嘟嘟嘟嘟嘟嘟！
- I'll be right back
with our lovers' special.
- 我马上回来
与我们恋人的特别。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
This is going so great,
SpongeBob!
这一切进展如此顺利，
海绵宝宝！
Karen is totally jealous.
凯伦非常嫉妒。
- Here we go.
- 开始了。
I whipped up a special batch
of chum for you,
我做了一批特别的
你的密友，
and for your lovely robot date,
为了你可爱的机器人约会，
a bucket of grease
chock-full of nuts and bolts.
一桶油脂
塞满了螺母和螺栓。
- Plankton,
I don't want to eat this!
- 浮游生物，
我不想吃这个！
- Don't you ruin this for me,
SpongeBoob.
- 你别毁了我的一切
海绵宝宝。
Just eat it!
就吃吧！
[metallic clanging, clattering]
[金属叮当声，咔哒声]
[both gulp]
[两人都咽了一口]
Ugh.
啊。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Oh, my dear
Shelby Naughtica,
哦，亲爱的
谢尔比·诺蒂卡,
you are the most
beautiful woman
你是最
美丽的女人
I've ever laid my eye on.
我曾经关注过。
- Oh, Plankton-poo!
- 哦，浮游生物便便！
You say the sweetest things.
你说着最甜蜜的话。
- [scoffs]
Oh, brother.
- [嘲笑]
哦，兄弟。
- I never knew what love was
until I met you.
- 我从来不知道什么是爱
直到我遇见你。
- Oh!
- 哦！
You have made me the happiest
girl robot in the world!
你让我成为最幸福的人
世界上的机器人女孩！
- Hey, you!
- 嘿，你！
Get your hands off my man!
把你的手从我男人身上拿开！
- You better step off, lady.
- 你最好走开，女士。
No one can make Plankton happy
like I can.
没有人能让浮游生物开心
就像我可以的那样。
We are soulmates,
and we're going to get married
我们是灵魂伴侣，
我们要结婚了
and print 1,347 babies.
并打印 1,347 个婴儿。
- 1,000 what?
- 1,000 什么？
- Oh, well,
you're really in love.
- 哦，好吧，
你真的恋爱了。
I won't stand in your way.
我不会挡你的路。
Plankton's all yours.
浮游生物都是你的了。
- Yeah!
- 是的！
- No!
- 不！
The whole point
of this scheme
整个要点
该计划的
was for me
to get Karen back,
是给我的
为了让凯伦回来，
and now
you're ruining it!
现在
你毁了它！
- Sorry, Plankton.
- 对不起，浮游生物。
You just said such
nice things to me.
你刚才说了这样的话
对我来说很好的事情。
- Wait a second.
- 等一下。
You're not just
being a jerk?
你不只是
是个混蛋？
You mean,
you cooked this whole
你的意思是，
你把这整个都煮了
stupid scheme up
to win me back?
愚蠢的计划
把我赢回来？
- Of course I did.
- 我当然这么做了。
I'd do anything
for you, baby,
我愿意做任何事
为了你，宝贝，
even hang out with
this moron.
甚至一起出去玩
这个白痴。
- Oh, that is so sweet!
- 哦，那太甜了！
- Get over here, you.
- 过来，你。
- [smooches]
- [亲吻]
Ew, it's that
fat screen saver again.
呃，就是那个
又胖了屏幕保护程序。
- What?
- 什么？
[smacking]
- Now, Karen, take it easy.
[咂嘴]
- 现在，凯伦，放轻松。
- I'm gonna go now.
[smacking continues]
- 我现在要走了。
[继续打巴掌]
- My motherboard
was right about you.
- 我的主板
关于你的看法是正确的。
She warned me about you.
- [yelping]
她警告我关于你的事。
- [尖叫]
- And I should have
listened to her.
- 我应该有
听她说。
[Plankton screams]
[浮游生物的尖叫声]